{
    "id": "da2596cea7ca454693bed40b0578be10",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What you said ……………………… unpardonable.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the noun clause 'what you said'. When the subject is a clause, the verb is usually singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They spoke in a low voice lest they ………………………. wake up the baby.",
            "description": "Should is the only auxiliary that can be used after lest. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "could",
                "should"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have invited them ……………………. dinner.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "for",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had called her, she ……………………… happy.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following words does not have a plural form?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Accommodation",
                "Pleasure",
                "Addiction"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Smoking is injurious to health. Here smoking is a ………………….",
            "description": "Ing forms used as the subject of a clause is a gerund. ",
            "answers": [
                "Present participle",
                "Adjective",
                "Gerund"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "There is a cottage ……………………… the river.",
            "description": "Above is preferred when one thing is not directly over another. ",
            "answers": [
                "over",
                "above",
                "across"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody came, ……………………?",
            "description": "Affirmative tags are used after negative expressions like nobody. In question tags, use they to refer to nobody, somebody, anybody. ",
            "answers": [
                "did nobody",
                "did they",
                "didn't they"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither fish nor meat …………………….. with me.",
            "description": "When you connect two singular subjects with neither/nor, the verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "agrees",
                "agree"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "To ruffle feathers is to ………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "encourage people",
                "excite people",
                "upset people"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Call them at once. Change into passive.",
            "description": "We use let to change imperatives into passive. ",
            "answers": [
                "They be called at once.",
                "Let them be called at once.",
                "They should be called at once."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister …………………….. abroad.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about permanent living arrangements. ",
            "answers": [
                "is living",
                "lives",
                "live"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}